An Inventory of the United States. Food Administration records XX066
Hoover Institution Archives
United States. Food Administration records
1909-1957 (bulk 1917-1919)
XX066
Hoover Institution Archives
420 manuscript boxes, 25 card files boxes, 34 oversize boxes, and 5 envelopes (223.6 linear feet)
The records relate to the regulation of food distribution and consumption in the United States and Allied areas during World War I, and include correspondence, reports, memoranda, minutes, press releases, surveys, statistics, printed matter, and photographs.
United States. Food Administration.
Access
Microfilm use only.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Herbert Hoover subject collection, Hoover Institution Archives
Poster collection, Hoover Institution Archives
Everett Somerville Brown papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Vernon Lyman Kellogg papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Alonzo Englebert Taylor papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Frank Macy Surface papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Mark Lawrence Requa memoirs, Hoover Institution Archives
Records of the U.S. Food Administration [USFA], Record Group 4, National Archives and Records Administration
Herbert Hoover Papers, Pre-Commerce Period, Herbert Hoover Presidential Library, West Branch, Iowa
Historical Note
"Food Will Win the War" was the slogan. Food had become a weapon in World War I, as European countries could no longer produce sufficient food for their populations. Since the U.S. had to provide food to its armies and the Allied armies, Allied civilians, and Americans at home, President Woodrow Wilson established the U.S. Food Administration (USFA) as an independent agency by Executive Order 2679-A of August 10, 1917 under the authority of the Food and Fuel Control Act (40 Stat. 276).
The USFA regulated the supply, distribution, and conservation of food. President Woodrow Wilson appointed Herbert Hoover to the post of U.S. Food Administrator, making the following statement: "In order to meet [the] shortage, every encouragement and direction possible was given to increased production." In addition, the conservation of food already produced was approached through the elimination of wasteful practices and unnecessary consumption. Herbert Hoover created his "Food Conservation" program, which Americans called "Hooverizing." According to the program, American households would eat less in order to leave food to ship abroad. Thus Herbert Hoover succeeded in cutting domestic consumption of food that was needed overseas and avoided rationing at home.
The USFA ended wartime food controls immediately after the Armistice on November 11, 1918. USFA conservation regulations lapsed in November-December 1918. Licensing requirements terminated in June 1919. The remaining functions of the Food Administrator were transferred to the Chief of the Cereal Division, USFA (wheat and wheat products) and to the U.S. Attorney General (all other food products). The USFA was finally disbanded on August 21, 1920.
Although the activities of the USFA were terminated at the war's end, its accomplishments laid the foundation for Allied post-war relief efforts in Europe.
Sources: History of the United States Food Administration, 1917-1919, by William C. Mullendore, with an Introduction by Herbert Hoover, 1941, Stanford University Press, Stanford University, California. National Archives and Records Administration; Herbert Hoover Presidential Library and Museum, http://hoover.archives.gov
For additional historical information, see: George H. Nash, The Life of Herbert Hoover, vol. 3, Master of Emergencies, 1917-1918. W. W. Norton, 1983
Scope and Content of Collection
The records relate to the regulation of food distribution and consumption in the United States and Allied areas during World War I, and include correspondence, reports, memoranda, minutes, press releases, surveys, statistics, printed matter, and photographs.
Documenting the establishment and organization of the USFA and its subsidiary agencies, the records include rules and regulations, policies, plans, and operational agreements with producers, refiners, manufacturers, and purchasers of various commodities.
The records are organized into 70 series by division, subject, personal office or physical form. Additional series have been created for later additions to the records.
Division records often include correspondence, predominantly outgoing, and chronologically arranged internal documents such as agenda, minutes and memoranda, governing documents, and periodical reports of activities, as well as financial records and issuances of the organization and its officials. Personal offices contain similar records, along with incoming correspondence, and often reflect the daily operations of an office within the organization.
The Alphabetical file, in three overlapping segments, lists subjects, terms, and names alphabetically. Files generally consist of reports, memos, minutes, correspondence, and regulations, from all divisions of the organization in alphabetical order by subject or country. Heavily indexed by the organization, the alphabetical file also includes cross-references to related files in the series and to the other numbered series.
Information on the public outreach program and the development of nationwide food conservation programs may be found in the Library and Exhibits Section records. The section created various visual aids and suggestions on how to organize exhibits and fairs related to food conservation at public places.
USFA records are also held in the Herbert Hoover Presidential Library and at the U.S. National Archives. Though they partially duplicate the records held at the Hoover Institution, the records include complementary materials, often about particular regions throughout the country.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 70 series by division, subject, personal name or physical form. Series 1-48H use division office codes designated by the USFA.
World War, 1914-1918--Economic aspects.; World War, 1914-1918--Food question.; World War, 1914-1918--United States.
- Microfilm Reel Content Guide
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- 1-H Herbert Hoover, U.S. Food Administrator files, 1914-1927. (Folder 1-7, 368-375)
  General note
  See also boxes 368-375
  - Appointments, 24 May 1917-1915 November 1918. (Folder 1: 1)
    Includes index of safe of Herbert Hoover, 1 March, 1919
  - Notes on National Food Control for Council of National Defense, March 1917 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Memoranda and Agreements regarding Allies and Neutrals and Data on Shipping and Exports (from Herbert Hoover's safe in the Food Administration), 1917 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Official Acts regarding Food Administration, miscellaneous contracts and agreements, legal opinions and reports, 1917-1918 (Folder 1: 4-5)
  - Food Administration, 1919-1927 (from the Secretary of Commerce Archive) (Folder 1: 6-7)
  - Introduction to the U.S. Food Administration, report by Herbert Hoover, April 1920, printed copy and drafts (Folder 1: 8-13)
  - The U.S. Food Administration, 1917-1920 Organization and Functions, by the Division of Classification, Washington, 1940 (Folder 1: 14-16)
  - Conferences, 1917-1919. (Folder 1: 17-18)
    See also 5-H; 6-H; 12-H; 15-H; 18-H; 35-H; and 39-H
  - Memoranda to Herbert Hoover, 1917-1920 (Folder 2: 1-15)
  - Memoranda to Herbert Hoover, 1917-1920 (contd.) (Folder 3: 1-8)
  - Memoranda to Herbert Hoover, 1917-1920 (contd.) (Folder 4: 1-2)
  - Copies of receipts of sugar, rice, sisal, ammonia, and ice, contracts and agreements filed in Herbert Hoover's safe in the Food Administration, Washington, 1917-1919 (Folder 4: 3-8)
  - Legal opinions and reports, correspondence, (from Herbert Hoover's safe), 1918 (Folder 4: 9-21)
  - Correspondence, 1917-1920. (Folder 4: 22-23)
    Includes reports, memoranda, proclamations, orders, rules and regulations
  - Correspondence, 1917-1920 (contd.) (Folder 5: 1-25)
  - Correspondence, 1917-1920 (contd.) (Folder 6: 1-11)
  - Ignace Jan Paderewski, Testimonial Dinner, 1920-1921 (Folder 6: 12)
  - Lewis L. Strauss, Secretary to Herbert Hoover, office files, 1917-1919. (Folder 6: 13-25)
    Includes correspondence, memoranda
  - Clippings, 1918-1919 (Folder 6: 26-28)
  - Clippings, 1918-1919 (contd.) (Folder 7: 1-3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1914-1919 (Folder 7: 4)
- 2-H Appointment Division records, 1917-1919. (Folder 7)
  See also 32-H
  - V. M. Hillyer and R. G. Phelps; applications, inter office memoranda and certificates of appointments, 1917-1919 (Folder 7: 5-7)
- 3-H Mail Department records, 1917-1918 (Folder 7)
  - L. A. Larsen, daily reports and mail resume, 1917-1918 (Folder 7: 8-9)
  - Lewis Barrington, inter-office memoranda, 1918 (Folder 7: 10)
- 5-H Home Conservation Division records, 1917-1920. (Folder 7-13)
  See also 9-H; 11-H; 12-H; 26-H; 27-H (Food Conservation)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, 1917-1918
    - Correspondence, reports, and memoranda, 1917. (Folder 7: 11-15)
      See also 6-H; 45-H
    - Writings, speeches, articles, statements, and notes, 1917-1918 (Folder 7: 16-22)
    - Writings, speeches, articles, statements, and notes, 1917-1918 (contd.) (Folder 7: 1-3)
    - Scrapbook on conservation, photographs, 1917 (Folder 8: 4)
    - Clippings, 1917-1920 (Folder 8: 5-11)
    - Clippings, 1917-1920 (contd.) (Folder 8: 1-5)
  - General Advisory Committee to Assist in the Organization of Home Economics Section, 1917-1918. (Folder 9)
    Includes correspondence, writings, inter-office memoranda, and minutes of meetings
    - Martha Van Rensselaer, New York College of Agriculture, Ithaca, N.Y., 1917-1918 (Folder 9-10: 6-12)
    - Sarah Field Splint, 1917-1918 (Folder 9: 13-14)
    - Alice C. Boughton, Secretary, 1917-1918 (Folder 9: 15)
    - Sarah Louise Arnold, 1917 (Folder 9: 1)
    - Isabel Ely Lord, Director, School of Household Sciences and Arts, Brooklyn, N.Y., 1917 (Folder 10: 2)
    - Abby L. Marlatt, Chairman, University of Wisconsin, 1917 (Folder 10: 3)
    - Fred Van Sicklen, 1917 (Folder 10: 4)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1917-1918 (Folder 10: 5-8)
  - Insignia, 1917 (Folder 10: 9-11)
  - Home Card Campaign, 1917-1918. (Folder 10)
    See also 9-H
    - First Home Card, 1917 (Folder 10: 12-13)
    - Office files, 1917 (Folder 10: 14-16)
    - Additional directions to First Home Card, 1917 (Folder 10: 17)
    - Memoranda, 1917-1918. (Folder 10: 18-21)
      Includes pledge card samples
    - Memoranda, 1917-1918 (contd.) (Folder 11: 1-2)
  - Vernacular Press, 1917 (Folder 11: 3)
  - Publicity Division, press releases, 1917-1918 (Folder 11: 4-7)
  - Campaign Pledge press statement, nos. 1-17, circa 1917 (Folder 11: 8-9)
  - "How the People of the Country Criticize the Policies of the Food Administration," report submitted by the Section of Mails and Files, 1917 (Folder 11: 10)
  - Statement of approximate total expenditures for the Conservation Group, 24 October 1917 (Folder 11: 11)
  - "Where the Food Campaign Fails to Get Across," an analytical study, 28 January 1918 (Folder 11: 12)
  - Publicity analysis report, October-November 1917 (Folder 11: 13)
  - Conservation Coordination and Policy Board, 1917-1918 (Folder 11: 14)
  - Cooperative organizations, agricultural, commercial, fraternal labor, patriotic, religious, etc., 1917 (Folder 11: 15-18)
  - Exhibit and campaign methods, John H. Cover, 1917. (Folder 11: 19-21)
    See also 12-H
  - Speaking Division, Mina C. Van Winkle, 1917-1918 (Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, reports, 1917-1918 (Folder 12: 1-2)
    - A Bulletin for Speakers, 1-6, 1917-1918 (Folder 12: 3)
    - Speaking itineraries, 1917-1918 (Folder 12: 4-10)
    - Letters and telegrams commenting on speaking tour, 24 January-15 March 1918 (Folder 12: 11-12)
    - Speeches, addresses, lectures, 1917-1918 (Folder 12: 13-17)
  - Publications, typescripts, printed matter, 1917-1918 (Folder 13: 1-11)
  - Miscellaneous illustrations, photographs, 1917 (Folder 13: 12-15)
  - Roger S. Baldwin, reports, 1918 (Folder 13: 16)
  - Florence Wardwell and Ethel Mather Bagg file concerning servants, 1917-1918 (Folder 13: 17)
  - "Food Administration Number," The Journal of Home Economics, 1918 (Folder 13: 18-19)
  - Bibliography of publications, 1917-1920 (Folder 13: 20)
  - Conservation for World Relief, 1918 (Folder 13: 21-22)
- 6-H States Administration records, 1915-1920 (Folder 14-39)
  - John W. Hallowell, 1917-1919. (Folder 14)
    See also 44-H
    - Relation between Enforcement Division and the Food Administration, 1917-1919 (Folder 14: 1-4)
    - Organization, 1917-1919 (Folder 14: 5-16)
    - Organization, 1917-1919 (contd.) (Folder 15: 1-4)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, 1917 (Folder 15)
    - Organization dossiers, 1917 (Folder 15: 5-12)
    - Reports on Michigan, Kentucky, Illinois, Indiana, Wisconsin, Iowa, Missouri, 6-29 December 1917 (Folder 15: 13)
  - Appointment of state food administrators, 1917 (Folder 15: 14-19)
  - Conferences of administrators, 1917-1918 (Folder 16: 1-8)
  - Speaking Division, W. A. Milne, 1918-1919 (Folder 16: 9)
  - State administrators as of 29 September 1917, 16 March 1918, and 1 May 1918, list (Folder 16: 10)
  - "Resume of Important Rulings and Letters" sent to federal food administrators, 1918 (Folder 16: 11-15)
  - Conservation and cooperating organizations, 1917-1918 (Folder 16: 16-17)
  - Assistants to John W. Hallowell, 1917-1918 (Folder 17)
    - Cecil Barnes, responsible for the sending out of letters and wires addressed "To All Federal Food Administrators,", 1917-1918 (Folder 17: 1-17)
    - Cecil Barnes, 1917-1918 (contd.) (Folder 18: 1-16)
    - Cecil Barnes, 1917-1918 (contd.) (Folder 19: 1-10)
    - Kent S. Clow, 1917 (Folder 19: 11)
    - W. A. Dupee, 1918 (Folder 19: 12)
    - Franklin W. Fort, 1918 (Folder 19: 13)
    - George W. Warrington, 1918 (Folder 19: 14)
    - Personnel of Food Administration, lists, circa 1918 (Folder 19: 15-16)
    - Four Minute Men, 1918 (Folder : 17)
    - Press Release, States Section, Education Division., See 12-H (Folder 19-39)
  - U.S. Federal Food Administration, states files, 1917-1920 (Folder 19)
    - U.S. Federal Food Administrators lists, 1918 (Folder 19: 18)
    - Alabama, 1917-1919 (Folder 19: 19)
    - Alaska, 1917-1918 (Folder 19: 20)
    - Arizona, 1918 (Folder 19: 21-22)
    - Arkansas, 1918 (Folder 20: 23)
    - California, 1918-1919 (Folder 20: 1-8)
    - Colorado, 1918 (Folder 20: 9-15)
    - Connecticut, 1917-1918 (Folder 20: 16)
    - District of Columbia, 1917-1918 (Folder 21: 17)
    - Delaware, 1917-1918 (Folder 21: 1)
    - Florida, 1918-1919 (Folder 21: 2)
    - Georgia, 1917-1918 (Folder 21: 3)
    - Hawaii, 1917-1918 (Folder 21: 4)
    - Idaho, 1917-1918 (Folder 21: 5)
    - Illinois, 1917-1918 (Folder 21: 6-9)
    - Indiana, 1917-1918 (Folder 21: 10-18)
    - Iowa, 1917-1918 (Folder 22: 19-20)
    - Kansas, 1917-1919 (Folder 22: 1-3)
    - Kentucky, 1919 (Folder 22: 4)
    - Louisiana, 1917-1918 (Folder 22: 5-6)
    - Maine, 1918 (Folder 22: 7)
    - Maryland, 1917-1918 (Folder 22: 8-9)
    - Massachusetts, 1917-1918 (Folder 22: 10-12)
    - Michigan, 1917-1918 (Folder 22: 13)
    - Minnesota, 1919 (Folder 22: 14)
    - Mississippi, 1919 (Folder 22: 15)
    - Missouri, 1917-1919 (Folder 22: 16)
    - Montana, 1917-1918 (Folder 23: 17-18)
    - Nebraska, 1917-1918 (Folder 23: 1-2)
    - Nevada, 1917-1918 (Folder 23: 3)
    - New Hampshire, 1917-1918 (Folder 23: 4-5)
    - New Jersey, 1917-1918 (Folder 23: 6-7)
    - New Mexico, 1917-1918 (Folder 23: 8)
    - New York, Allen Fox, Head of Bureau of Licenses files, 1917-1920 (Folder 23-27)
      - General correspondence, reports, printed matter, 1917-1919 (Folder 23: 9-10)
      - Bread and bread making, 1917-1918 (Folder 23: 11-14)
      - Brokers, 1918 (Folder 23: 15)
      - Bulletins 4-100 (incomplete), 1918 (Folder 23: 16)
      - Butter, 1918 (Folder 23: 17)
      - Canned goods, 1918 (Folder 23: 18)
      - Cheese, 1918 (Folder 23: 19)
      - Coffee, 1918 (Folder 24: 20)
      - Combination sales, 1917-1918 (Folder 24: 1)
      - Commission Merchants, Bonded and Licensed, agricultural bulletin, 1917 (Folder 24: 2)
      - Corn and corn meal, 1918 (Folder 24: 3)
      - Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Folder 24: 4-5)
      - Cotton seeds, 1918 (Folder 24: 6)
      - Dried fruits and vegetables, 1918 (Folder 24: 7)
      - Eggs and poultry, 1917-1918 (Folder 24: 8)
      - Enforcement Division, 1917-1919 (Folder 24)
        - Policy, penalties, and prosecutions, 1917-1919 (Folder 24: 9-16)
        - Alan Fox, private cases, New York, 1918-1919 (Folder 24: 17-20)
        - Reports, 1918-1919 (Folder 25: 21-22)
      - Fair Price Committee, 1919 (Folder 25: 1)
      - Feed and feeding stuffs, 1918 (Folder 25: 2)
      - "Fifty-Fifty," Wheat Conservation Plan, 1918 (Folder 25: 3)
      - Fish, 1918 (Folder 25: 4)
      - Flour, 1918 (Folder 25: 5)
      - Food Conservation Week for World Relief, 1918 (Folder 25: 6)
      - Fox, Alan, Head of the Bureau of Licenses, correspondence, 1919-1920 (Folder 25: 7-13)
      - Fruits and vegetables, 1918 (Folder 25: 14)
      - Hotels and restaurants, steamships, 1918 (Folder 25: 15)
      - Households, 1914, 1918 (Folder 25: 16)
      - Lard, 1917-1918 (Folder 25: 17)
      - Legislation, 1917 (Folder 26: 18-20)
      - License Division, 1918-1919 (Folder 26: 1-2)
      - Malt, 1918 (Folder 26: 3)
      - Margins, 1918 (Folder 26: 4)
      - Mayor Mitchel's Food Supply Committee, printed matter, 1917 (Folder 26)
        - Garden Primer, How to Plant and Care for a Vegetable, 1917 (Folder 26: 5)
        - Hints to Housewives, 1917 (Folder 26: 6)
      - Meat, 1918 (Folder 26: 7)
      - "Memorandum on the Coordination of the Federal, State and City Food Activities in the State of New York, ", 1917 (Folder 26: 8)
      - Merchants Association of New York, report of The Food Problem Committee, 1918 (Folder 26: 9)
      - Milk, 1918 (Folder 26: 10)
      - Mills and milling, 1918 (Folder 26: 11)
      - Profits, 1917-1918 (Folder 26: 12)
      - Rationing, 1918 (Folder 26: 13)
      - Reports of the New York State Food Commission, 1917-1919 (Folder 26: 14-17)
      - Resales, 1918 (Folder 26: 18)
      - Rice, 1918 (Folder 26: 19)
      - Rye, 1918 (Folder 26: 20)
      - State and City Food Board, 1917-1918 (Folder 26: 21-24)
      - "Store-Door Delivery," report of Committee on Prevailing Rates for Trucking, circa 1917 (Folder 26: 25)
      - Sugar, 1917-1918 (Folder 26: 26-27)
      - Sugar, 1917-1918 (contd.) (Folder 27: 1)
      - Transportation, 1918 (Folder 27: 2)
      - Warehouses, 1917-1918 (Folder 27)
      - Correspondence, reports, and contracts, 1917-1918 (Folder 27: 3-5)
        - American Warehousemen's Association, Incorporated, 1918 (Folder 27: 6)
        - Cold Storage, 1918 (Folder 27: 7)
        - Complaints, 1918 (Folder 27: 8-9)
        - Questionnaire, 1918 (Folder 27: 10-13)
        - Rates, regulations, and rules, 1917-1918 (Folder 27: 14)
        - "Reports on the New York City Warehouse Situation, ", 1918 (Folder 27: 15)
        - Standard Warehousemen's Guide, 1917-1918 (Folder 27: 16)
        - Wheat, 1918 (Folder 27: 17)
      - North Carolina, 1917-1918 (Folder 28: 1)
    - North Dakota, 1917-1918 (Folder 28: 2)
    - Ohio, 1917-1918 (Folder 28: 3)
    - Oklahoma, 1917-1918 (Folder 28: 4)
    - Oregon, 1918 (Folder 28: 5)
    - Pennsylvania, Howard Heinz Federal Food Administrator files, 1916-1920 (Folder 28)
    - Acknowledgements, greetings, 1917-1920 (Folder 28: 6-9)
      - Addresses, 1918 (Folder 28)
      - "A Year of Food Administration in Pennsylvania,", August, 1918 (Folder 28: 10)
        - "An Outline of the Work of the Federal Food Administration in Pennsylvania, ", 1918 (Folder 28: 11)
        - Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Folder 28: 12-16)
      - Notebooks, circa 1917 (Folder 28: 17)
      - Organization, 1917-1918
      - By subject, 1917 (Folder 29: 1-5)
        - "To All County Federal Food Administrators, ", 1918 (Folder 29: 6-15)
        - "To All County Federal Food Administrators, ", 1918 (contd.) (Folder 30: 1-5)
        - County organization, circa 1918 (Folder 30: 6)
        - Accounting, 1918 (Folder 30: 7)
        - Addresses by Herbert Hoover, Alonzo Taylor, and Ray Lyman Wilbur, 1917-1918 (Folder 30: 8)
        - Advertising, outdoors, 1917 (Folder 30: 9)
        - Agriculture Department, 1916-1918 (Folder 30)
        - Machinery, 1918 (Folder 30: 10)
        - Publications, 1916-1918 (Folder 30: 11)
        - Allies, rations, 1918 (Folder 30: 12)
        - "American and Allied Ideals," by Stuart P. Sherman, War Information Series, Washington, D.C., 1918 (Folder 30: 13)
        - Army and navy, 1918 (Folder 30: 14)
        - Authority, 1918 (Folder 30: 15)
        - Bakers and baking, 1917-1918. (Folder 30: 16-18)
          See also Bread; Wheat and Flour
        - Barley, 1918 (Folder 30: 19)
        - Beans, 1918 (Folder 30: 20)
        - Beef, 1918 (Folder 30: 21)
        - Binder twine, 1918 (Folder 30: 22)
        - Bread, 1918. (Folder 30: 23)
          See also Bakers and baking; Wheat and Flour
        - Breakfast cereals, 1918 (Folder 30: 24)
        - Brewing, 1918 (Folder 30: 25)
        - Bulletins, 1918 (Folder 30: 26)
        - Buttons, 1918 (Folder 30: 27)
        - Candy, 1918 (Folder 30: 28)
        - Canning and canned goods, 1917-1918 (Folder 30: 29)
        - Cards, 1917-1918 (Folder 30: 30)
        - Car-Lot Distribution, by J.S. Crutchfield, President of Cruthfield and Woolfolk, Pittsburg, Pennsylvania, 1916 (Folder 30: 31)
        - Chain stores, 1918 (Folder 31: 1)
        - Churches, 1918 (Folder 31: 2)
        - C.H. Heintzelman, Secretary, Chamber of Commerce, Coatesville, Pennsylvania, 1917-1918 (Folder 31: 3)
        - Coffee, 1918 (Folder 31: 4)
        - Cold storage, 1918 (Folder 31: 5)
        - Colleges, 1918 (Folder 31: 6)
        - Combination sales, 1917 (Folder 31: 7)
        - Commercial Economy Board, 1918 (Folder 31: 8)
        - Commercial travelers, 1981 (Folder 31: 9)
        - Committee of Public Safety, 1917-1918 (Folder 31)
        - Outline of departmental activities, 1917-1918 (Folder 31: 10)
          - "To the Chairman," etc, series 1-46, 1917-1918 (Folder 31: 11-16)
          - Conferences, 1918 (Folder 31: 17)
        - "Conservation Week, ", 1918 (Folder 31: 18-19)
        - Corn meal, 1918 (Folder 31: 20)
        - Costs, 1917-1918 (Folder 31: 21)
        - Cotton, 1918 (Folder 31: 22)
        - Council of National Defense, 1918 (Folder 31: 23)
        - Crop and Livestock reports, 1918 (Folder 31: 24)
        - Crutchfield, J. S., 1917-1918. (Folder 31: 25)
          See also box 30
        - Dairy and dairy products, 1918 (Folder 32: 1-2)
        - Damaged food, 1918 (Folder 32: 3)
        - Demobilization, 1981-1919 (Folder 32: 4)
        - Dietary for miners, 1918 (Folder 32: 5)
        - Dog law, 1917-1918 (Folder 32: 6)
        - Draft law, 1918 (Folder 32: 7)
        - Dried fruits, 1918 (Folder 32: 8)
        - Eggs and poultry, 1918-1919 (Folder 32: 9)
        - Enforcement, 1917-1918 (Folder 32: 10)